（ディソナス）うわっ！
（ナルト）うぉ～！
（カブト）僕なんかに構ってて
いいのかい？
なんか
大変なことになってるみたいだよ。
Are you sure you should be
spending your time on me?
（カカシ）我々を甘く見るな。
Because it seems like you've got
some trouble on your hands...
あれも何とかなるのかな？
Don't underestimate us.
Are you going to do
something about that too?
クッ…　クソッ！
ナルト！
Naruto!
（九尾）死ぬのか？
（九尾）ここで死ぬのか？
Are you going to die?
Are you going to die here?
（九尾）つまらんやつめ！
That good-for-nothing...
フフフフ…　貸してやるぞ　力を！
《力…》
I'll lend you some...
"Power"...
Power?
((ミナト：コントロールを…　力の…))
《力の…　コントロール…》
（サクラ）ナルト～！！
Control... your "power."
《まだ…　終われねえ！》
Control my "power"?
((ミナト：必ず出来る。
Naruto!
(信じてるよ…　お前を…))
たぁ～っ！！
I can't. let it end here.
I know you can do it.
I believe...
in you...
うぉ～っ！！
always chasing after your shadow
itsu made mo oikakete iru anata no zanzo wo
when you dream, your face looks like it did before
yume ni miru yokogao ha ano koro no mama de
you run into the tall grass and disappear
se no takai kusanami ni hashiri satte kieta
I push through the memories and follow you
omoidasu kioku wo kakewake atoo uboku ha
it's frustrating as I run out of breath and in the end I'm unable to reach you
modokashiku mo iki wo kirashite saigo ha todokazu ni
far away
tooku
how many years ago was it?
nannenmae no koto desho
I left my heart at that place
nidoto modorenai ano basho ni
where I can never return
oite kite shimatta boku no kokoro sa
if this is a dream, if I can't get it back
moshimo yume naraba tori modosenai no nara
then how can I tell you how I feel?
kono kimochi ha do shite utaereba ii no
I'm still chasing after the shadow from that day
imadani oikakete iru ano hi no zanzo wo
though I spend my days in sorrow
kanashimi ni ake kurenagara mo ima
I'll live on in this world without you
anata naki sekai de boku wa ikiru yo
うぉ～！　とりゃ～っ！！
（サイ）すごい…。
（ヤマト）だが…　九尾化じゃない。
（サクラ）ナルト…。
逃げたか…。
ナルト！
That's amazing...
But... it's not
the Nine Tails transformation.
ドックさん！
ここは危険です！
早く避難しないと。
Naruto...
（ドック）でも…　あれを止めないと。
He escaped...
Naruto!
わかっています。　我々に任せて…。
（ドック）僕は→
Dokku!
僕は　馘首になったけど
この村の防人でした。
It's dangerous here!
You must get away.
ここを…　ホールを守るのは→
But...I must stop that.
僕の責任です。
I know. Leave it to us.
わかりました。
I...
I was fired,
but I used to be a village guard.
（シセル）一人じゃ無理。
ダメだよ。　危険だよ。
Protecting this place...
the "Hole"...
お兄ちゃんの今の体力で
ちゃ～んと　たどり着けるの？
is my duty.
お願い…　一緒に…。
All right
（ミィナ）先生。
You can't do it alone.
（ファズ）行っちゃ　やだ。
（レオ）行かないでよ！
No! It's too dangerous!
You think you can get there
in your current condition?
（みんな）先生！
みんな…。
Please, let's go together.
Sensei...
I don't want you to go...
Don't go!
— Sensei!
All of you...
ファズ　好き嫌いは　もうダメよ。
まずくても　贅沢言わない。
力をうんとつけて
みんなを守って。
ランド　年長らしく　しっかりな。
みんなが困ってたら
助け合って　頑張って。
Faz, you can't be
picky anymore.
ソラ　みんなの世話をしてあげてね。
Don't complain even
if it doesn't taste good.
ミィナの面倒　よくみてあげて。
You need to become strong,
and look after everyone.
レオ　これからは
つらいことも悲しいことも→
Lando, you're the coldest,
so take charge.
いっぱいあるかもしれないけど
みんなを支えて　頑張れ。
If anyone's in trouble,
help them.
Do your best.
Sora, take care of everyone.
ミィナちゃん。
Especially Mina...
Watch over her.
お願い　ミィナ！
Leo, there may be
tough times ahead,
あの時　ひっぱたいて　ごめんね。
and sad times too.
ミィナだけが　ナルトお兄ちゃんが
おかしいことに気づいてたのに→
But do your best to
help everyone out!
わからなくて…　ごめんなさい。
これから　とても大変だと思う。
Mina...
でも　くじけないで　頑張って。
Please, Mina!
お兄ちゃんや　みんなと一緒に→
I'm sorry I slapped you that day.
強く生きてね。
You were the only one who sensed
that Naruto wasn't himself...
I didn't realize it.
（ミィナ）うわぁ～ん！
I'm so sorry!
Things will probably
get tough from here...
But hang in there and
do your best!
短い間だったけど
楽しかったよ　みんな。
I want you, your brother,
and the others...
本当に幸せな時間だったわ。
to be strong, and live!
ありがとう　みんな。
ありがとう。
愛してるよ。
愛してるわ。
We weren't together too long,
but it was fun.
皆さん　子供たちをお願いします。
They were such happy times.
はい。
全力で守ります。
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
シセル！
I love you.
シセルさん！
先生！
All of you...
Please look after the children!
Yes.
We'll do everything in our power.
Shiseru!
お兄ちゃん！
— Sensei!
（ドック）もし…　もし
これを生き延びられたら。
えっ？
もし　生き残れたら→
結婚しよう！
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Brother!
If...
If we make it out of here alive...
やっと言った。
Huh?!
If we make it out of here alive...!
じゃあ　何が何でも
生き残らなきゃね。
Let's get married!
うぉ～！
You finally said it!
Well then, we're gonna get
through this,
no matter what!
とぉ～！
ハハハ…　ガハハハ！
（ドック）あった！　さえずりだ！
あいつは　パターンの組み合わせだ
って言ってた。
どんな？
わかんないよ。
There it is! The "Saezuri"!
If only we can operate this.
There it is.
The village chief had that!
あっ！
そうか…　ミィナのメロディーだよ。
あの子が　ずっと前から
口ずさんでた　あれだ。
That guy said it was
the combination of sounds.
Like what?
I don't know.
殺せ　壊せ！
世界のすべてを！
That's it!
Mina's melody!
これできっと…。
The one she's always been humming!
（カカシ）ナルト！
あっ！
ナルト！　まずい
完全に我を失ってる！
何！？
Kill... Destroy...
the entire world!
キャッ！
あっ　あぁ…。
This should work!
Naruto!
（ドック）シセル！
シセル～！
うわぁ～！
（３人）あっ！
あっ！
Naruto?!
This is bad!
He's completely lost control
of himself!
What?!
早く登って。
ダメ。　脱臼したみたい。
えぇっ！
サクラ　僕を回復してくれ。
（サクラ）え？
（サイ）早く！
Shiseru!
すまない。
いえ。
（ヤマト）でも　九尾の力が強すぎて→
いつまで拘束できるか
わかりませんよ。
苦しんでる。
ミィナ！
Hurry... Climb up!
I can't... I think it's dislocated!
Huh?!
Sakura... Heal me.
What?
Hurry!
ダメだ！　何か次の手を打たないと。
— Thanks!
— Don't mention it.
The Nine Tails is too strong,
I don't know if I can
keep restraining him!
He's in pain.
負けないで。
Mina!
You guys?
お兄ちゃん　もうやめて。
覚悟はできてる。
イヤだ。　離さない。
時間がないのよ。　私なんかより
早く天の矛を止めて。
I can't do it!
絶対イヤだ。　僕の大好きな人が
また落ちるのを見るなんて→
We have to try something else!
もう絶対イヤだ！
（ドック）好きだったよ。
ずっと　ずっと　ずっと。
だから必死につかんでたのに
ごめんよ。　ごめん。
だから　もう二度と離さない！
離すくらいなら一緒に落ちる。
私も　あん時から
ずっと惚れてんだから。
Don't give up...
私のほうが背が高くなっても→
どんどん太っても
ハゲても　グズでも臆病でも→
私から逃げてばっかりでも。
それでもやっぱり
ずっと好きだったんだから！
Brother, stop it.
I'm prepared to die!
でもね　あの子たちは誰が守るの？
No! I won't let go!
There's no time left!
あなたしかいないの。
Hurry and stop
the "Ama no Hoke"!
あの子たちの未来は
あなたしか救えないの。
Like hell I will!
I'm not going to watch
the person I love fall again!
でも…　でも…。
Never again!
I've loved you! Since forever
and ever and ever!
That's why I desperately
held on, but...
I'm sorry.
I'm 50 sorry!
That's why ['ll never let go again!
If I do,
we'll fall together!
I've been in love
with you too, since then!
Even if I grew taller...
お願い　助けて…。
And you kept getting fatter,
and lost your hair...
Even if you were indecisive
and scared of everything...
Even if you kept turning away
from me!
((守りたい　助けたい
大切な人たちを…　友達を…))
All that time, I still loved you!
But who's going to protect
the children?
パパと　ママを…。
You're the only one!
((ドック：信じてる。
（ミナト）信じてる。
You're the only one who
can save their future!
(（ドック）キミの正しい力を。
（ミナト）お前を…))
But... But...
（ランド）ナルト兄ちゃん！
（ソラ）お願い！
助けて！
僕たちの…。
（みんな）パパとママを！
世界を救って。
あの子たちを　守ってあげて。
Please... save them...
愛してる…　愛してるわ。
To protect... my friends...
those dear to me.
私の大切な…。
I want to save my friends.
My papa and mama...
I believe...
— I believe in your power...
— in the good inside you.
In you.
Brother Naruto!
Please!
Save them!
Our...
— Papa and Mama!
Please save the world...
and protect...the children...
あ…　ナ…。
ナルト君！？
おっちゃん　そいつを早く止めろ！
I love you...
I love you so much...
my precious...
邪魔を…　するんじゃねえ！
おぉ～！
うおぉ～！
Na...
Naruto?
Mister!
Hurry up and stop that thing!
うおぉ～！
Don't get...in his way!
ナルト兄ちゃん！
ナルト兄ちゃ～ん！
おっ！　重てえって　ちょっと！
助けてくれて　ありがとう　ナルト君。
Hey, help me!
ありがとう。　本当に　ありがとう。
There's nothing more
you can teach me.
おう！
What are you saying?
There's much more
to Reanimation...
I got all the data I need
from this experiment.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Ch, and I'm taking the strong ones
you assembled.
美空ひばりです。
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Why you—!
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』→
２時間スペシャル。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手の→
Get your revenge.
Why?
I don't need him anymore.
Besides, I never liked him.
Wait! He's the one
who destroyed the village.
He manipulated the shinobi!
Stop! No, stop!
Mama! Papal
Brother Naruto!
You guys are heavy!
Thank you for saving me, Naruto!
Thank you!
Thank you so much!
Sure thing!
"Power"
Dear Naruto,
I haven't written in a while.
How have you been?
I'm sure you already know,
but the Saezuri which controls
the "Ama no Hoko" of the Hole
has left in the care of
the Land of Fire,
and it has been sealed away deep
in a secret place.
The villagers have been told
of the tragic happenings
and many came to
offer their prayers.
We are all filled
with gratitude.
By the way...
Shiseru and I were married.
And we legally adopted
the children.
They are a lively bunch and
we certainly have our hands full...
but every day is a joy.
Mina just had a birthday
and turned five,
Her previously red hair and eyes
have darkened now.
We think it's because the powerful
influence of the Hole is gone.
I can't say it enough...
But thank you very, very much.
The fact that my life is so rich now
with Shiseru and the kids...
is all due to you and your power.
I hope that you will never
find yourself astray again.
Please use your power joyfully...
and use that power to
help your friends.
I'll pray for that
with all my heart.
All of us are truly grateful
and wish you joy and happiness...
Thank you!
I wonder why I can't fly
nande kanaa sora ga tobenai no wa
even though in my dreams, I have wings
yume no naka no boku wa hane ga haeten no ni
I'm going to surpass my limits and leave this place
genkai wo koete tobidasou koko kara
I'll drive away my loneliness with you
samishisa fuki tobasu kimi to kimi to
"I love you" and "good bye" have disappeared
i love you mo sayonara mo ienakatta
leaving me here incomplete
koko ni fukanzen na boku dake wo nokoshite
you still haven't taught me the song of love
ai no uta kimi ni mada tsutaetenai yo
of this dazzling world
dokomademo mabushiku kagayaku sekai wo
of this song
kono uta wo
I guess I'll head out to see them.
Next Episode
Madara, I'll never forgive you for
resurrecting the Jinchuriki
with the Reanimation Jutsu!
I'll end this war!
Naruto's now able to sense
his enemies.
He has no choice,
but to join the battle.
All according to plan!
Today, the Senju's Will of Fire
will be extinguished!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Naruto Enters the Battle"
Naruto Enters the Battle!!
It's time for me to make my appearance!